[laughter]
>> Yeah, I called the show "Shamik
Chakrabarti Live". I thought it's a
great name for the show. Then some
comedy experts from the industry told me
no, if you want to be taken seriously as
a comedian,
which is already a funny statement.
Then you have to like name the show. It
has to have a name name, okay? So, I've
named it. It's called "Despite
Appearances".
>> [music]
>> You guys ever go to the cinema hall to
watch a movie and during the movie they
say the title of the movie in a
dialogue?
And you notice it, right? You're like,
"Hey,
that's the that's the name of the whole
thing."
They try [laughter] to sneak it in,
right?
When I was a kid, I remember, "Welcome
to Jurassic Park." The moment I heard
that, I was like, "Oh, thank god."
Cuz 10 minutes had passed, no dinosaurs,
you know? I was beginning to worry, am I
in the right theater?
So, this is what we're going to do. At
some point during the show, I will say
the show name again. I've already told
you the name. All you have to do is just
go crazy.
>> [laughter]
>> Like mad, LIKE PEOPLE BE LIKE, "WHOA!"
LIKE SOME magic trick has happened. Can
you do that? Yeah?
Okay, awesome. Perfect.
You guys ever walking down the street
and you remember something you've done
that's so stupid that you do this you do
this to yourself? Have you ever done
that yourself? What
and ruins your whole day, yeah? I'll
tell you my story. There's no time to
hear yours.
Two years ago, maybe the stupidest thing
I've ever done.
Uh
I had this brand new laptop and I left
it in an auto rickshaw and I got off.
Brand new.
Bra- I hadn't pressed all the keys yet.
>> [laughter]
>> Some of them have like F3 I had not
looked at also.
Who looks at F3?
I was I was going from one comedy club
to another in Mumbai. I got off at the
second comedy club. I'm walking into the
comedy club and I do this, you know, to
check for my bag.
It was not.
I didn't panic. I'm like, I have another
shoulder.
It's probably on my spare one.
That's why we have two.
So, then I do like this.
Now we're panicking.
Shoulder check complete.
Shoulder two, bag zero.
What should you do in this situation?
You should run out. There is no point
thinking. I'm too arrogant to run. I'm
like, I can't let the world know I have
messed up.
So, I think for 15 seconds I just stood
there and thought about it.
How has this happened? My my
my bag used to be on my shoulders.
My shoulders are here.
Where is the bag?
In that time the auto was gone.
I stepped out on the road. I looked both
sides.
Gone. So, I do what any logical person
does, right? I take one more step in
both sides. I'm like,
You know, you do that as if in that step
the auto will reveal itself. Oh, there.
From here you can't see it. Suddenly
>> [laughter]
>> it did not reveal itself.
Now, my first thought at this moment
should tell you something about me.
My first thought was, no one that I know
can find out this happened.
Huh? Getting it back is the second
thought.
Firstly, no one can know.
I'm like, my family can never know. I
decided. If my parents found out, guys,
to them immediately I would become
person who lost laptop.
Who happens to be our son. Son would be
a footnote.
I would They'd call me laptop loser.
That would be my new name in the house.
What does it say about Indian parenting
that a 30-something year old man thinks
about his parents and what they will say
when he lost his own laptop.
Which he bought with his own money.
Which by the way
they didn't know existed at this time.
So, think about that. First, I would
have to call them and be like, "Good
news, I bought a laptop."
"Now, don't get too excited. The bad
news
48 hours later,
>> [laughter]
>> I have reversed the process. I have
unbought
said laptop."
Which I knew I would tell them because
they have trained me.
I'm sure many people are Indian parents.
They train you over the years. You don't
even realize it. There is this sickening
honesty inside me. I end up confessing.
It's like I'm a secret agent reporting
on me.
To them.
Sometimes while I'm telling them, my
brain is like, "Bro, why are you doing
this?"
There's no need.
>> [applause]
>> And I'm like, "Wait, you are my brain.
Who gave the command then?
How many brains are there?"
So, anyway, I was standing there
panicking, and the security guard at the
comedy club, he saw my face. He said,
"What happened?"
I said, "I left my laptop in the auto
and it's gone." And the guard did this.
He's like,
Like 50 times he moved his hand.
Every time he's doing this, in my head,
laptop was going farther.
I'm doing this. I'm canceling it.
>> [laughter]
>> It's like uh
when Ajay Devgan dance step, you know,
right?
You know, he can't move his legs, so
they just make him move his hands.
>> [laughter]
>> Also, he's not just this. He was like
this switch. You know, right? That angle
There's some angular to linear distance
conversion in India, which no one has
worked out yet.
But we know, like, this is far, but this
is like
It's gone next galaxy.
I'm going to come back to 12:00.
Nothing he said was helpful, this guy.
First thing he's like, "There's a Dell
showroom here. Get a new one."
What is this boy attitude, bro?
I just lost it. I can't move on.
Not yet.
>> [laughter]
>> Next he's like, "Bhoool jao. Forget
about it."
"She belongs to Mumbai."
Bhoool jao.
How many stages of grief are left before
bhoool jao?
I told him, "Listen, man.
I can't tell my family about this. You
are my family, right?
Just send me in a direction. Get me
moving cuz I'm frozen right now. Tell me
next step." And he's like, "Yeah, go to
the police station. Nothing will
happen."
"Don't have hope. Just go.
Everybody goes in this situation, so you
also go."
So, with this level of hope, I start
walking
to the police station, right? And as I'm
walking,
then I felt this I have this
self-loathing in me which was rising,
you know? Any of you have it? Like, it's
good to have a little bit. You should
like hate yourself a little bit. It's
good for
keeps you in check, but I have a lot.
All right. And it was rising in me.
It helps. Like, in this profession,
doing comedy in India, it's good to have
it because in India, you put a joke
which you think is your best joke you'll
ever write. One guy.
>> [laughter]
>> He'll be like, "Worst."
Not only that, they'll be like, "This is
not a joke."
That hurts more. Like, it's not They're
not defining it as what I define it. Bad
joke is okay. This is not the thing
you're trying also.
>> [laughter]
>> Luckily, all those comments the
algorithm inside has already said it
before only to me.
Has nada get you.
I say that to myself when I the joke.
So, your comments don't affect. Which is
not to say today you go and comment some
hate on all.
No, no, it affects me. I'm kidding.
Actually, it affects me when I'm not
expecting it. That's when like when
you're like when people find an angle to
hate you didn't see it. I put a joke
online about being tall. I was like,
"How much hate can you get for this,
dude?"
>> [laughter]
>> I was shocked. Dude, all these guys
started DMing me, "Hey, bro, are you
showing off?"
"Height is not a joke, bro. Height is
just height, dude."
"Bro, what is the height? Why work on
your personality? Why you got
Why you relying on height to impress
impress the chicks and all?"
They were saying things you can't deny.
Like one guy was like, "Bro, if I was
tall,
I would also be tall."
Fair enough.
>> [laughter]
>> Can't deny that.
LHS equal to RHS. Because LHS is RHS.
They're like, "Bro, you don't even look
that tall in this video. Why you lying
to people? I think I'm way taller than
you."
"If I meet you, I'll prove it. I'm I My
shoulder is higher than yours."
"Shoulder is the main one. Height is not
really important in the
Hold a coin next time for perspective."
>> [laughter]
>> All these 5'11s were messaging.
>> I'm not saying all 5'11s are like this.
Some I can sense some are here.
Not all, but the ones who are messaging
were 5'11. I can tell.
Come on, guys. 5'7 is not messaging.
They know height is not my battle to
fight.
Only 5'11s were like all They're all
Some 5'11s they stand like this all day.
They're like, "One more inch I wouldn't
need a personality."
Hey, measure me now. No, this is the
same. I won't I'm only doing so. Measure
measure now.
You know what you get with this height?
You get back pain. Every person my
height, irrespective of age or
geography, has back pain.
I'm not saying regular height people
cannot have back pain,
but everyone my height has it. I know, I
check.
I see someone on the street my height, I
go up to them. "Excuse me."
100% of the time they're like "Oh."
It's like all the time. And then we feel
empathy for each other. So, we rub our
backs together like this.
It's our sex position.
99 I call it.
>> [laughter]
>> One niner
flipped, whatever.
If you see two tall people rubbing backs
in public, keep walking.
They're healing each other. This is not
for you.
All right? You keep taking your tiny
steps.
Get home before sunset.
Dangerous out there.
I injured my back recently
during football. Football was happening
and I was there.
Was I playing football?
>> [laughter]
>> You decide. You decide if this counts as
an athletic injury.
Let me say what I was not doing, which
is I was not running.
I was not No one was running, actually.
No one was near me.
I did it to myself,
but on a football field.
This is true. I injured my back
placing the ball.
Just for a corner. Like this motion
My body couldn't do.
Even now I'm not committing to it fully.
I'm scared.
>> [laughter]
>> And not small injury. I was out for
months.
This moment. Ow. [laughter]
I had to go to the doctor directly in
full football gear.
Not a drop of sweat.
First minute I got injured. You know how
difficult that is?
Before sweat.
I remember the clinic. I went to the
clinic, there were older people there.
They saw me fully kitted out and they
were like, "You go first." They thought
some athlete has come.
Like half time of the cup final he has
come.
Like he must be he has his name on his
back. He must be
They didn't know I paid money for that.
>> [laughter]
>> They didn't know it's not my name. I'm
not Zidane.
They had no ball knowledge in the
clinic.
>> [laughter]
>> I opened that doctor's door with my leg
to just use my shin pad once.
That day, you know? I wore it.
This There was I was in pain, but guys,
this pain was nothing compared to the
pain caused
by the words of the doctor.
This doctor, he's a medical doctor he
claims.
You know what he said to me after I told
him how I got injured? He's like, "Yeah,
don't bend from your back." [laughter]
I was waiting for more reason.
You bend from your back. I'm like,
"Who asked you?" I mean, who asked me?
>> [laughter]
>> I have to be asked
to bend from my own back?
Dude, I've been giving myself permission
all my life.
I didn't know I'm doing it wrong. He
literally said you should never bend
from your back. Guys, you don't know
this? You should never bend
>> [laughter]
>> from arguably the bendiest part of your
body.
Looks like it's designed by the gods to
mainly bend.
>> [laughter]
>> It's always asking you but you should
just rigid you should whole life
should live like this.
Wake up in the morning don't bend to you
just roll out of bed like this.
Fall on your face break your nose it's
fine. Back is important.
He said the next thing you might guess
he said bend from your knees. I'm like
first of all doctor if you want me to
call you that.
Cuz you're very close to mister the way
you're treating me.
>> [laughter]
>> Like you want me to do something write
it on the prescription.
I came for that I didn't come for
advice.
You're a doctor.
>> [laughter]
>> He's like okay don't bend from me.
There's a lot of blank space in brackets
you know three times a day.
One dash one dash one.
Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> I I asked him a question he had no
answer for at that point.
I doctor I watch a lot of football how
come I never saw one professional
footballer
take the corner like this.
They should do it right?
He had no answer.
But
honestly guys jokes aside you should
listen to your doctor. So I did.
And it was the wrong decision.
Cuz the week after my injury I had to go
to Japan for a few days.
And uh
>> [laughter]
>> I ended up insulting everyone by
mistake.
Every time people are like thank you I'm
like oh you're welcome.
And they're like no no you have to obey
prescription.
Doctor said I can't greet you like that.
>> [laughter]
>> So, you need a prescription otherwise it
looks like a hate crime, you know?
Just for this joke I went to Japan. Can
you believe it?
This is how much I do for you.
I didn't go to Japan, all right? Like if
you believe that, what's wrong with you?
Come on.
I went to the next best place. I went to
uh
tiger reserve
>> [laughter]
>> in Karnataka.
Why is it the next best place to Japan?
Cuz that's where the next joke happened.
It's not always possible to write a
segue between jokes. [laughter]
I'm just speaking about my experience.
Okay? And my experience of this place uh
is uh
that calling this place a tiger reserve,
in my opinion, huge insult to the deer.
Huh? [applause]
That tiger to deer ratio was
unacceptable.
If you want to call it tiger, if the
name is on the board, 3 hours of finding
one tiger.
About 7 crore deer.
Why is it a tiger reserve?
Five of us were in a jeep entering the
gate, all right, of this tiger reserve.
>> [snorts]
>> Dude, one deer was outside the gate.
He was eating grass outside then he went
in. It's just like he came to a
restaurant and he went back home.
They're just employees at this point.
>> [laughter]
>> He did a biometric scan and he got in.
The moment the safari started I knew
something is wrong. Like I've never seen
arrogance in deer before.
On a safari you see deer, they are
always,
like any moment I could die.
These deer, they were walking up to us.
They were like,
Yeah.
He's also deer.
The moment I saw that attitude, I'm
there's no tiger here.
This is pure no tiger behavior.
Maybe a vegan one, HUH?
I FELT BAD for our guide. We had a tour
guide, and every passing minute he was
getting desperate. He's like, "What do I
show them?"
>> [laughter]
>> It's a bigger deer.
This is big. So, forget that one. This
is big.
Same one, big.
It's getting bigger if you keep looking
at it.
It was. You know why? Cuz we are driving
towards it.
No credit to the deer for that.
At one point, this is 3 hours of safari.
2 and 1/2 hours into it.
He's like, "Can you guys see that
branch?"
>> [laughter]
>> That means he gave up on land animals.
It's like, "Today animals are out of
office."
Plan B, take them aerial.
>> [laughter]
>> And the next words he said, guys, these
infuriated me. He's like,
"On that branch, that is our famous wild
crow."
How dare you
show me a crow in a forest?
Show me no animal,
but don't show me a crow.
I don't call it wild crow.
Lost crow.
>> [laughter]
>> We took that crow to Bangalore with us.
You see in his eyes, he's missing
Parle-G right now.
Wild or does it do cocaine? Like, why is
it wild?
Whenever uh
it's going bad, right, on a safari like
this, they do this to get your attention
back. They just switch off the jeep.
Yeah, anyone experience that? Yeah?
And then it works. Everyone except me
was like,
Like the deer will bite you now.
>> [snorts]
>> I was not impressed. I asked the guide,
I'm like, "What happened? Is it tiger
time? Have we reached the tiger's house?
It's almost over, so I'm like, is it
new? Tiger is" And the guide was like,
And then he whispered in my ear. He's
like,
"Actually, uh, you will scare the
tiger." He said, "I'll scare the tiger?"
I'm like, let me tell you something,
man. Uh,
if I can scare a tiger with my voice,
I don't want to see that tiger.
That's not the kind of tiger I signed up
for.
Please tell the tiger I'm not ashamed of
it.
Forget it. I'll bite the deer.
They were mating at this point in front
of us, making more deer.
This confidence I don't like.
Don't start mating. If animals start
mating in front of me, dude, I I become
different. I'm like anti-Romeo squad at
that point.
We saw one elephant and, uh, for those
who are keeping count, this last two
animals in this joke.
If you're getting worried, it's the
whole show animals. Two more.
It happens, so I'm telling you.
So one elephant and the guide forgot his
own advice about keeping the volume
down. He's like, "HEY, ELEPHANT!"
THAT WAS THE SCARIEST PART OF THE whole
thing.
Because imagine if the guide is
surprised.
The guy who does this three times a day
is like,
>> [laughter]
>> I'm like, was there not supposed to be
an elephant? Has it broken into the
tiger reserve?
He's like, "You can see from the bulge
she is pregnant right now, 11 to 12
month." Elephant heard this
and charged at us.
You see those YouTube videos where you
are the Jeep is going in reverse?
Elephant is running. In video it looks
slow, it's very fast.
We got away, but
as [clears throat] we were driving off
I'm looking at the guide and I'm like
And he replied with the same gesture.
This is a beautiful, versatile gesture
we have.
>> [laughter]
>> It can be a question
and the answer to that question.
Context would be completely I don't know
what his meant.
But mine meant
What is wrong with you?
It also meant, and I don't know if you
can communicate so much with one
gesture,
but it also meant
same rules as with humans, never assume.
Let her tell you.
Speaking from experience.
>> [cheering]
>> Speaking from having misidentified many
pregnancies.
Um
let them tell you.
>> [laughter]
[laughter]
>> EVEN IF I HEARD THAT SOUND AT THE SAFARI
I WOULD'VE BEEN LIKE THIS WAS WORTH IT.
>> [applause]
[cheering]
[clears throat]
>> WE SAW ONE TIGER AT THE END. IT HAD A
zip on the back.
>> [laughter]
>> All the way along the back was a zip.
I don't know there's any Indian zip back
tiger,
but I've seen one.
The first one ever.
I can't be 100% sure, but trust me guys
I saw I saw what I saw, all right? First
of all, it was the last animal we saw in
the 3-hour safari. How convenient.
It appeared right at the end when we had
given up.
In the distance, never close, far away.
Sunset. He stepped out for a second,
disappeared behind the bush.
And the guide was like, "You will never
see it again." And he was sure.
That's why I'm like, "Huh, of course he
called it, right?"
Behind that bush, that tiger is smoking
a cigarette right now.
I can't be 100% sure, but I had a new
prescription. I saw a zip. Take it, you
believe me, you don't believe me, I'm
sorry.
My only regret is from that that whole
evening.
My only regret is if I had the courage
that day, guys, to get off the jeep
and unzip [clears throat] that tiger.
There's a non-zero chance two deer would
have come out.
I think deer are doing every job in the
forest.
It's a costume party for the deer.
There were no other animals there.
Elephant was not pregnant, it's a deer.
The whole elephant also, it's like seven
of them.
Guide is a deer and zips his face, he's
like,
"Everyone's a deer."
I go home, I am a deer.
I've seen all the deer I want to see in
my life.
If a deer comes walking in, I'll shoot
it.
This concludes the animal part of the
show. Thank you, you've been wonderful
so far. Clap for yourselves, amazing,
>> [applause]
>> amazing crowd.
Don't clap so much also. Wow, when I say
clap for yourself, it's never ending.
>> [laughter]
>> Or maybe you have two, three lines.
Oh, for us?
We are the best.
Back to the human stuff now.
I'm walking towards the police station,
if you remember. [laughter]
Huh?
And this is this is Mumbai, is the
Bandra police station and true story I
used to live next to it at the time next
to Bandra police station. I never gone
in before. First time I would have to go
in.
And
even passing a police station you see
interesting things sometimes. If you pay
attention like you know like smaller
cases.
Indian police are like solving outside.
This one we're not taking inside.
Al fresco.
You'll be passing outdoor they're
solving it. You'll see a two guys are
just doing like this.
That is the law.
That is that kind justice.
>> [applause]
>> At least they're bending from their
knees you know.
GOOD FOR YOUR
IT'S GOOD FOR YOUR HEALTH.
IF THEY TAKE YOU inside you could be
bending from who knows.
I've heard I don't know.
So I get to the police station and there
was a policeman standing at the entrance
he's looking out it's like he was
looking for a case.
So I gave him one.
I show up he's like what happened? I
said I left my laptop in the auto
rickshaw and it's gone. And the first
thing this policeman said is
why you chose that? Why did you leave
it?
Not where or when.
Straight to the philosophical.
Like what is in you
that made you do this? Think about it.
Indian police they want you to
introspect first
before helping you. It's like a therapy
free therapy session.
They're like why you brought work for
me? Think about it.
Why did you leave the laptop? That's not
a question you're meant to answer. You
have to just stand there if you don't
know. You have to just stand there and
look guilty.
He's like why you chose that? What sir?
You can move your hands. It doesn't have
to mean anything.
It's whatever.
Stand there long enough and look guilty.
I was just
And he's like, "Okay, enough. Go
inside."
This is a true story, by the way. The
tiger zip I made up. This is real.
This happened.
Now, picture the scene. There are three
policemen sitting on a long table and
same face. All three had same frame
mustache.
But, as [snorts] you move to the right,
they were like
taller and bigger. Like
Like, you know Russian doll? You know,
like
You've seen those doll? You open it and
a smaller version is inside.
It was like a police Russian doll.
At night, you can put this guy inside.
Pack them up. They were just sitting
three of them like that. Like a human
Adidas sign. They were just sitting
there.
And um
So, I go to the first one, the left.
he said, "What happened?" I said, "I
left my laptop in the auto one day."
This policeman's only contribution to
this case,
I'm going to directly quote to you now.
He said, and I quote,
"You look outside with the at the first
guy."
And that guy was like, "Huh?"
>> [laughter]
>> And then he said, "Go to the second
guy." That's it. His whole contribution.
I don't know what other sounds he's
capable of.
For my case,
over.
Sent me to middle policeman, slightly
taller. And this is true.
He had a notebook, I remember. Brand new
notebook he had in front of him. He had
I think it's new.
Navneet 240 page
unruled. He believes in himself.
He doesn't need laws in the book to stay
within the lines. I am the law.
I'll write like this if I want.
He opened a new book. He wrote his name
first page.
Drew one sun
with alternating lengths of Why do we
all do the alternating lines anyway?
Two birds, of course.
Never one. It feels lonely. We always
draw two.
And then he opened the book. He's
looking at me. It felt like random. He's
like,
"Tell me your address." He said, "My
address." He asked, "The one address in
Mumbai
where I am sure the laptop is not
there."
"The one I have eliminated from the case
is the one he wants." But I'm like, "At
least let me humor him. He's asking a
different question than the others." So,
I start telling him my address. And
remember I said I live next door. So,
obviously when you say the address, you
use your hand automatically, right? I
swear to you, I never forget this. I I
told him I started telling the address.
I'm like, "I live here only." He saw my
hand
and he drew one arrow IN THE BOOK.
WHO DOES THAT? What is that?
I'm like, "Am I high right now, dude?"
Who takes the address in that detail?
Now, he can't turn the book. My address
will be wrong now.
He nailed it down to the table. It's to
always be
He wrote my address and then he said,
"Next police." He was the address
police.
There are so many
highly specialized roles in the police
station.
Final policeman he sent me, tallest one.
Next to him is a wall.
Either he helps me or I was hoping he
takes my head and just smashes it.
That's how I felt in that moment.
But he asked the important question,
"Where did you leave the laptop?"
And I told him where, and he said, "You
are in the wrong police station.
This is Bandra, that's Khar police
station."
>> [snorts]
>> 40 minutes I've been in this police
station
because they've been asking me why I did
it,
not where. [clears throat]
And now he's like, "Jaldi ja." I'm like,
"Well, it's over.
My motherboard has been shipped."
>> [laughter]
>> Guys, I'd like to believe the police
were extra harsh with me that day
because they expected more from me.
I'm a victim of people's expectations,
and also I have this face of a
responsible citizen.
Sensible face, I think people think this
guy is stable, he will do the right
thing. He's low energy, must be
sensible.
>> [laughter]
>> No, I just
I have like front bencher face,
back bencher brain.
So, this combo confuses people
sometimes.
Uh I'm not complaining, it's helped me
in my life.
Really has. I've never been fired from a
job.
I should have been.
Many times. [laughter]
Many times.
If there's one thing I'm proud of in my
corporate career, guys, it's my
consistency. I
never gave it my all.
You can learn something from me. Never
show them your 100%.
>> [laughter]
>> They will think this is it.
Dude,
what happens is, right, when your team
under performs in a company, which it
always did when I was there,
they don't fire the guy with this face.
>> [laughter]
>> They're like, "Not him, he was thinking
up ideas.
The others let him down."
Uh you should enter the office and just
sit quietly.
People think you're thinking of
something. They can't believe you can be
blank for that long.
I would just sit and look at my boss and
he would get worried.
I'll look at him with that attitude
like, "What? This is the team?"
>> [laughter]
>> Bro, you want me to work with
Fix all this, then I'll show you what I
can do.
You should sit with that attitude. No
one will fire you. You should be like,
"How can you fire me? I didn't DO
ANYTHING."
THERE IS NO PROOF OF ME DOING ANYTHING.
HOW ON what basis I do
No action proves I have done anything
wrong.
My parents have been fooled by my face.
I was born with exactly this face.
Smaller body.
They They saw me. They were like, "We
nailed it."
Didn't have a second kid. Only child.
>> [laughter]
>> Like, "One and done."
"He will do whatever we ask him to do.
Look at that face."
10 fixed deposit face.
So, this career choice I have made in
this country
in this time
is just to teach them a lesson.
>> [laughter]
>> It's not my direct passion to do comedy.
It's to scare them.
To remind them you should always have a
spare.
>> [laughter]
>> I am a bit of a man-child. I have
accepted this about myself. And I think
I know where the problem started. It
started when I was 12.
When I decided
adulthood not not interested.
Based on my dad's favorite four words.
Growing up, my dad had this catchphrase.
I thought it's a catchphrase. And the
words were, "Attested PAN card Xerox."
All through my childhood
he would say these words on the phone to
people, in his sleep.
His life revolved around attested PAN
cards, Xerox.
Either he was sending it or he was
receiving, sometimes both.
Multiple copies.
And I didn't know what's happening. All
I knew was this is adulthood.
This is what it's about. I have to do
this one day and I won't enjoy it.
Honestly speaking, it's turned out to be
true. That is adulthood.
>> [laughter]
>> In fact, all the conversations with my
dad now are in three categories. One,
I'm sure this is relatable. First
category, I'm telling him
that WhatsApp forward is fake.
Right? Every dad, this is universal. I
performed in UK and Australia. I checked
there also dads are doing this.
[laughter]
They just forward things. After some
years, they don't care anymore.
Three times last year my dad sent me
Ajay Devgan dead.
>> [laughter]
>> Three times. And three out of three
times he was He's more alive now.
More Vimmal he's having, the more
fit he's becoming. Third time I was
like, "Dad, this is embarrassing. Even
other dads figured it out after two."
I told him, "Next time, go to Ajay
Devgan's Wikipedia. Read the first
line."
>> [laughter]
>> It'll say, "Ajay Devgan is
then he is."
That's all Wikipedia is useful for now.
Please do this check.
In fact, I'll be honest. I have a sick
hobby.
>> [laughter]
>> I can't be the only one. When a
celebrity passes away, right? I try to
rush to their Wikipedia page.
Like, can I catch it before they change?
So, the little thrill I feel, like,
so I screenshot it. I
tweet about it. "Come on, Wikipedia!
It's been 13 milliseconds since
this person passed. But, uh, 10 years
I've been trying. It's impossible.
>> [laughter]
>> Don't waste your time.
Wikipedia is too fast.
Seriously, it's like the ECG is
connected to the first paragraph.
Moment it flatlines was.
Sometimes they change it and then they
die.
I think it's like a mafia in Wikipedia.
Once you change you have to take them
out.
Oh, we made it was. Oh.
Fixed it.
Second category of conversation with my
dad is sports. We talk about sports and
we think we're having a real
conversation.
I was thinking the other day if we
remove sports from my dad and my life,
our the movie of our life would be
silent film.
That's all we really talk about. He
tries to bring other topics like did you
do your taxes? I'm like goal.
And I rush out when he's checking the
goal.
Next fiscal year I visit again.
But the third and most important
category of conversation with my dad
even to this day, every now and then
he'll call. He's like, "Yeah, send me
one attested."
PAN card and
Send one other also just in case. What
is this just in case?
Which case is this?
I'm simply xeroxing and sending.
Have you ever seen a situation where
people are like, "Oh, everything is it's
over." Oh, he sent other also.
And we are back.
This operation can continue.
>> [laughter]
>> I used to ask him earlier, "Why am I
sending? I sent it just few days back. I
warm the paper still warm from the
previous xerox."
I don't ask anymore. I'm just like he
loves it, dude.
He loves every He's retired. Every
person has their vices, you know. My dad
says he's addicted to documentation.
So now I just to humor I preemptively
send it now.
Like other pan, enjoy.
Every few days I'm sending.
Front and back, back and front.
Side and side, everything. You fold the
paper, my face kisses my own ass.
Right hand signature, left hand
signature.
Both hands signature.
I write this way and then I tie my first
name, last name in a bow in the middle.
I take a A4 sheet, I put ink on it, I
put my face in it.
Can clone your son, you have so much
info now.
>> [laughter]
>> It's pretty immature, I know.
>> [snorts]
>> So anyway, the the second police
station.
Guys remember, no, where we were?
The car police station. You can look
this up after this. It's like 3 km from
the Bandra police station, but that
evening it took 40 minutes.
That's just the beauty of Mumbai. I
mean, it happens here also, but
sometimes someone is in a real hurry.
The city senses it and they come
together to stop.
Everyone works beautiful. Everyone works
together. Suddenly in that moment the
truck in front of you
it will turn sideways
and then all the wheels will fall off.
>> [laughter]
>> 20 minutes it took me. I reached the car
police station, there was a policeman at
the entrance there also. They're always
there.
You just don't notice.
And I swear to you, it's like the first
police station called the second one.
And said one tall guy is coming.
He looks responsible, but he's not.
>> [laughter]
>> Ask him why he did it.
Start with why.
>> [laughter]
>> It's the only explanation. That second
police station I got the same line of
questioning. What happened? Left my
laptop. You told her.
I had a second attempt at this. I didn't
want to mess it up again. I changed my
answer.
He said you told her I'm like you came
out too tall.
So.
I was like maybe if I insult myself in
front of the police you get to the next
level of this game.
And I was 100% right. The moment I said
my two tears are good. Go upstairs.
>> [snorts]
>> First time I went above the ground floor
in this quest.
The level changed.
I raised one flag.
>> [laughter]
>> Music changed.
I remember as I was going he said go to
third floor talk to inspector so and so
in cyber crime. I'm like
Technically yeah, laptop was involved.
What is it cyber?
Crime didn't happen in the cyber world.
The side.
Technically it's not a crime. He's like
listen we've sent it to them already.
Go.
Send it to I am it.
This is it being sent. I am going to
tell them.
Anyway, I went to the third floor and I
walked into this big room and there was
a policeman and a civilian in he would
be in his 60s the civilian and no one
else I could see in the room. I swear to
you guys I walked in on this moment.
The civilian was telling the policeman
how his brother earlier that day stabbed
a guy.
He was doing the action like a policeman
doesn't know what a stabbing looks like.
And when I walked in he put the knife
away which is like
All right.
All right Daniel Day Lewis.
>> [laughter]
>> And the policeman looked at me. They
both looked at me. What happened? The
policeman asked. I spoke in keywords.
I'm like auto laptop.
I'll never forget this moment. This This
civilian, this uncle.
>> [laughter]
>> He heard what I said. He's like,
"Laptop? How can you forget laptop?
It's so big."
I'm like, "Uncle, your brother is a
murderer."
One day, focus on your family, yeah?
Indian uncles,
any side quest, they'll catch it.
Yeah, my brother murders sometimes, but
how can you lose a laptop?
Also, this is cyber crime department.
How is this
brought to the
Possibly the most offline crime of all
time
is in the cyber Everything is cyber
crime now.
I think they're like, "Does the victim
own any technology? Give it to Give it
to cyber."
Police policeman said, "You sit outside.
I'll finish with him in 2 minutes and
come."
This did not feel like a 2-minute
conversation.
>> [laughter]
>> And I was correct. It took 40 minutes.
The shortest unit of time. Smallest unit
of time when you are in a hurry in the
police station, 40 minutes.
You guys understand, like, 40 plus 40
plus 40 minutes have passed since I've
lost my laptop. Forget laptop, I had
lost my mind.
I was sitting outside of
There's footage of me in that police
station of
Tuesday,
Thursday.
>> [laughter]
>> Policeman came out after 40 minutes.
And he had hope in his eyes, this man.
He gave me hope again. With his hope. He
is like, "Don't worry, we have CCTV
access to all restaurants and pubs in
car. We will find the number plate of
your auto."
>> [clears throat]
>> I got goosebumps. He's like, "We'll find
your laptop." I'm like, "Damn, I didn't
know police can say things like this."
And I swear to you, he said this to me.
Then he sat in front of the computer,
which he said will solve everything.
And this is really clicked. One one
click of the mouse. And like 10 fatal
errors came on the screen.
Fatal it had it had the skull and the
bones like
10 of them like
I think it got bigger as the cascading
happened.
And I've never seen someone lose hope
this fast.
He's like, "We'll find it." One click
Like every one more tab was opening.
He's just looking at me like
>> [laughter]
>> And then he did something I'll never
forget like You guys ever tried to
explain your dream to someone?
And then while you're saying it, you
realize this makes no sense.
There's no logic to my I was awake and I
saw a dream.
This moment it was still permanent in my
head. After he did
Then there was an awkward silence. And
to fill that
He there was a landline phone. It didn't
ring. He just picked it up. HE'S LIKE,
"HM?"
>> [laughter]
>> HM.
HM.
HM. OKAY.
>> [laughter]
>> AND THEN HE HE ACTED like he did that
for me.
Like he tried one more thing to help me.
>> [laughter]
>> And that also didn't work. I'm like,
"Bro,
that's not how phone calls work. It
didn't ring. You knew when to pick it up
intuitively.
Nobody said hello.
>> [laughter]
>> You didn't ask a
Mhm, doesn't count.
You got your answer. You think I'm
stupid?
I am stupid.
That's a brand new laptop.
And an auto.
I was just like
My body language was all wrong at that
point. I had completely lost hope. Like
I was like I was just just sitting there
and I was like
I'm like, "What do I do now?"
He said, "You go to that cabin. My
senior inspector is sitting. You talk to
him." I'll talk to anyone.
I'm here to talk only.
>> [laughter]
>> I'm not I'm not leaving this police
station.
I asked him, "Ideally, arrest me.
Keep me two nights. I'll forgive myself.
Laptop is gone. Now it's about punishing
yourself."
He's like, "We are full right now.
Outside, two guys are doing squats. You
can join them if you want."
I'm like, "I've
done my three for the day."
>> [laughter]
>> So, I'm walking towards the senior
inspector's cabin. And remember I said
there [clears throat] is this hater
inside me louder than any outside hate.
That hater started talking loudly. He's
like, "Shamik, you piece of
If only you drove your own vehicle.
This could like it's less likely you
lose your laptop
in your own car.
But you won't drive.
You want to be driven [clears throat]
like a king.
>> [laughter]
>> Because you can't drive.
Which is not true. I can drive. It's
just It's complicated.
I'll tell you what happened. I learned
to drive in India, which let's be honest
with ourselves. In India, you don't
really learn to drive.
In India, you drive.
India learns how to avoid you.
That's the process.
Get out there. 1 2 years everyone's
like, "Yeah, I'm going to manage." I
don't think you appreciate until you go
outside India how much we treat driving
like an art. It's an art in India. Most
countries it's a science.
We are just expressing ourselves.
Every day you can change your technique.
Today I'll hold the steering like this.
It's fine. No one will say, "Hold
there." Other country they're like, "Put
it there." You can do anything. You
little finger.
You can blow it to turn.
As long as you can survive, you're a
good guy.
Enjoy.
Even you know the lanes we of course the
lane discipline thing I don't want to
get into.
>> [laughter]
>> Even the guy painting the line sometimes
the line goes like this. Have you seen?
>> [laughter]
>> He gets bored. He's like, "Why every
line straight? After I'll paint one like
this."
He lies down and paints it along his
body.
Everyone's expressing themselves.
>> [laughter]
>> In India the term expressway has nothing
to do with speed.
We are expressing ourselves. This is an
art all of this.
Oh, that car is coming wrong way on the
flyover.
Sometimes art must go against the
conventions of society.
>> [applause]
>> This is society. That is art.
>> [laughter]
>> So I learned in India. I was an artist
in the streets.
>> [snorts]
>> Accountant in the No, I was an artist in
the streets.
Uh but then what happened? I moved to
the US for 4 years. I learned their way
of driving. They have only one way.
They're boring.
Boring. I learned their sterile dull way
of driving. I forgot our way.
They removed the art from me.
I'm not an artist anymore.
I came back first day I saw the road and
I was like
Driver, Gary Nikhailo.
>> [laughter]
>> It's quite awkward cuz I didn't have a
driver or Gary.
>> [laughter]
>> Starting the BMTC guy.
If you're judging me that how can you
forget driving? It can happen to you
also, like
Like okay, how once you guys got used to
Western style
did you come back to Indian style?
No, it's hard on the knees.
Same [laughter] thing.
Um
I'm being dramatic. I can drive. It's
just that if you This is a warning to
you. If you see me drive, watch out.
>> [laughter]
>> I am damn dangerous. If you see me on
behind the wheel, watch out because I am
I am following all the rules.
In a society where rules are a
suggestion
the guy following them is the danger.
Like I'm stopping at the red light at
2:00 a.m. People behind like
>> [laughter]
>> They're judging me like does guy scared
OF A COLOR?
AFTER MIDNIGHT, WE treat it like a
color. Like red, yellow, green, enjoy.
It's just to beautify your drive.
Add some hues to your experience.
Which color will it be when I cross the
line today?
America me up, dude. I can't do it
anymore. Americans don't know how to
drive. First thing I noticed there on
their streets, their school buses drive
slow. What is that?
What is that, dude?
Show some put some effort.
You need to learn Have you seen Indian
school bus?
If it finds an opening
>> [laughter]
>> a yellow blur it is. It's flying.
Did you notice? Biggest vehicle on the
road is flying.
Can't read the school name in one
attempt.
One pin code you see, it's gone.
It's always in a hurry as if school is
important.
Right?
Do we have the best education system in
the world? No.
But you won't miss a minute of it.
The guy will get you there. Book,
cockroach, you are there on time.
I was once in a traffic jam where an
ambulance was stuck.
School bus found a way.
Found a gap where no one could find one.
>> [laughter]
>> We all clapped.
We were like, "Put the patient in the
school bus."
Way more motivated than this ambulance.
Nothing, no wow wow. He just believed in
himself.
>> [laughter]
>> You have to believe in yourself. You
can't wow wow your way through the whole
day. In India, sometimes wow wow doesn't
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm also wow wow.
You don't know what I'm going through
today. I identify as ambulance right
now.
Since we're on this topic, my school bus
driver, dude, he was a psycho. I'll
never forget him. He used to drop us
so early, like before sunrise sometimes
we used to reach. School was a sunrise
point.
The gate was locked. Is that not a sign
you're too early? The gate guy has not
come.
He drops us outside.
Basically, this man, he took children
from the safety of their homes
>> [laughter]
>> to outside a building
at night essentially.
Dropped them there. Stray dogs were
around. You know, before sunrise, stray
dogs are different.
So, we lost one of us every now and
then.
It's okay. We learned many lessons like
that.
All my lessons I learned outside the
gate, nothing inside.
Where do you think he went after
dropping them? He went to get more kids.
I learned [snorts] the meaning of hustle
from this man. This guy daily seven,
eight trips a day. He just never stop.
>> [laughter]
>> He's working on commission. How many
children can I deliver to the
before assembly. That's why we have to
get up at 3:30 in the morning.
In the fog I'm standing, me and some
friends. Water bottle the size of me
hanging over here.
I'm hanging on the water bottle.
It's insane work ethic. He's just like
going for the personal best every day.
Just kept the kids in different uniforms
he was bringing.
>> [laughter]
>> Brown pants, gray pants. You have pants
come.
He'll find a place for you. 6,000
children he has dropped.
School's total intake 400.
He's driving around like, "Hey, you want
to go to a school in this direction?
Try a new one. Come."
No uniform. Say it's your birthday.
Come.
That's why you can imagine my
disappointment in the American school
bus driver. So slow, dude.
Keep stopping.
Little pebble on the road they'll stop.
They'll remove it. Oh my god.
Mhm.
Got to get that out of the way.
You have a great day, all right?
They start making conversation, you.
If there's one thing I can say about
America, my experience there is this.
Strangers
will force you to have a great day.
Just minding your business. Hey, you
make sure
you make sure you have a great day. No,
I had other plans.
Why are you putting this pressure on me?
I was planning to have a bad day, it's
easier.
When a school bus stops in America, if
you've been there or you might have seen
in movies, every vehicle stops, not same
side, other side of the road they stop,
everywhere. You heard a rumor of a
school bus,
you stop.
Throw the key out of the window.
It's the biggest rule in their driver's
manual, never cross a standing school
bus. Kids might be getting off or on,
you know.
That's how much Americans care about
school children on the way to school.
HUH?
>> [applause]
>> ON THE WAY, they really care, like
safest country for going to school
in the world.
USA, no one talks about it. Once you
reach
school bus,
safety standards drop a bit.
We kept you safe on the way.
Life is ABOUT THE JOURNEY.
DON'T WANT TO LOSE ONE ON THE WAY to the
war zone.
No soldier left behind.
>> [laughter]
>> Most of my thoughts I would classify as
dark or disgusting or a combination.
And I don't blame myself.
I blame the internet.
Internet made me who I am.
Internet suddenly there
You ever go to the internet with good
intentions? Internet changes your plan
suddenly.
I was on Instagram seeing basketball
reels. I love basketball, good clean
fun, basketball.
I made a mistake, I went to the comment
of this reel. Never do that.
There were no humans in the comment.
They were all
sex bots.
You guys know this? Like they're these
AI generated bikini women. Why am I
doing the hands? Whatever, YOU GET IT.
IT'S ALL AI, AI bikini woman with AI
bikini comment.
On a basketball reel. Basketball reel
she's saying who wants to come over.
Three rockets.
>> [laughter]
>> How far is your house?
Three rockets up there. I don't have
time for this.
>> [laughter]
>> One more basketball reel to verify went
to another one comment section with
different sex but who wants to see my
I don't have to spell it out for you,
right?
P U
dollar dollar Y.
>> [laughter]
>> Dollar dollar so you know money is
involved.
And more than one so two dollar minimum
lot of information there.
Every basketball reel had these sex
bots. I was disgusted. I when in doubt I
blame America. I'm like these Americans
again they're trying to pervert us.
Made it a national issue. They're
perverting us innocent Indians.
These dirty sex bots, you know.
Then I really must have I said let me
see an Indian sports reel.
I'm sure the comments will be sports
related.
Can sense you're ahead of me on this.
So at the time I went to this ISL you
know the Indian Super League it's a
football league which as of now it may
or may not exist.
But it's a ISL is called Indian Super
League. It's a bit of a misnomer.
Super?
How about decent?
How about okay? I O L.
Anyway I just went to the Indian Super
League page. I saw one guy score a goal.
I'm like easy I scored that any day
without a back injury.
Then I went to the comments.
She was there also.
With one bindi.
She's acquired our culture.
Just that they like that they have like
that should do it. Everything else is
same.
That's not strictly true. One thing was
different. Her words were very
different. Cuz it's an Indian bot.
>> [laughter]
>> Indian sex bot has to cater to
what it thinks are Indian sensibilities.
>> [laughter]
>> So I yes, I will share with you now
the exact words of the Indian sex bot.
Only one disclaimer, don't judge me for
these words. As the I I'm not the author
of these words.
I'm Think of me as a journalist. I'm
reporting what I saw on the field.
Anyways, I'm journalists, you allow them
to say anything. Only comedians are NOT
APPARENTLY.
SO [cheering]
>> [applause]
>> THINK OF ME AS A sensationalist
journalist. Indian sex bot said,
remember what American one said for
comparison. Who wants to see my Who
wants to Classic boring.
>> [laughter]
>> Indian sex bot said
I can't look at you when I say this.
>> [laughter]
>> Sex me so much.
Indian sex bot said This is a direct
quote.
>> [laughter]
>> Con mera doodh piyega?
Who wants to drink
>> [laughter]
>> my milk?
There were more sex bots, but my eyes
stopped working at that point. I was
wearing glasses, but my glasses fogged
up. They like
>> [laughter]
>> Who wants to drink my milk?
Does that tell you something about where
we are economically as A COUNTRY?
BUT EVEN HER DIRTY TALK IS nutrition
based. You understand?
Economists, they keep talking numbers.
Words tell you everything.
Come on, man. Indian. That's uh You're
like, "Yeah, I'm on it, but is F&B
included or
make a day of it?"
Who wants to drink my Hopefully your
child, madam.
This is not the forum to check these
things.
So, the senior police inspector
This story hurts me, so I say it in
parts.
He was the coolest guy. He didn't ask
any questions. He had answers. He's
like, "Get on my bike. We'll go find the
footage."
True story. Me and the policeman, we
retrace my steps from that evening. We
went first to the first comedy club that
I had walked out of. You might know this
club in Mumbai. It's famous. It was in
then Yeah, some musical chairs happened
there recently.
It's called The Habitat. And next to The
Habitat, there was a brewery, and I had
walked out from the brewery at 6:00 p.m.
Picture the scene. 10:00 p.m. Thursday
night. Same brewery.
100 people are drinking beer. In the
middle of them, there's a pillar, and me
and the policeman, we are rewinding
footage.
And by the time we found me, all 100
were watching.
We had an audience. And they were
hammered.
>> [laughter]
>> One guy saw me in the footage, he asked
for my autograph.
I'm like, "Dude, this CCTV you are you
are also there, old
Why are you here from 6:00 p.m.? Go
home."
In this footage, we see me, and luckily
I had my bag, because as you're
rewinding, I had this horrific thought.
What if in the footage also
my bag is not there? Because when you
lose something like this, you
>> [clears throat]
>> you lose faith in yourself. You don't
know when you have messed up.
In this footage, if I didn't have the
bag, I would be like, "Did I even own a
laptop?
Am I hallucinating?
Sir, go home, sir. I made a mistake.
You would have slapped me, the
policeman. And these 100 people, they
were invested.
But I'm there and the bag is there. And
we see me walk out of the building with
the bag, but we don't see auto. It's cut
off there, the camera angle. So, all we
proved with this is I exist.
I could have told you that.
>> [laughter]
>> It's 10:30 at night. We step on the
street. Across the road, there is a
building office building. There was a
camera I saw in the first floor, I
remember. I said, "It's There's a camera
there. Shall we check that out?"
Policeman said, "Come."
I'm in the police now.
I'm a commanding officer.
No, he's the commanding officer. We went
to the first floor and he knocks on the
door.
Police. Which is less scary when you are
on the same side of the door.
So, a word of advice, if ever police
knocks on your door,
jump out of the window, join them.
Break into your own house. Quite
empowering. Maybe just open it for them.
>> [laughter]
>> There was a guard in this He's doing the
night shift at this office.
The policeman asked him that He said,
"We need CCTV access." The guard said,
"Only one guy knows the password.
2 months we've not been able to
contact."
And true story, the cop said, after
thinking for a second, he's like, "You
try admin at 123."
Capital A, admin at 123. He typed it,
logged in.
>> [applause]
>> I was so impressed, I forgot I had lost
my laptop.
I almost gave him a chest bump.
Whoopati pays, we became.
And he was like, "It's always admin at
123."
>> [laughter]
>> Then we rewind the footage. In this
footage auto is there.
I am not there.
Me and auto never in the same frame.
Am I auto?
>> [laughter]
>> That's the stupidest thing I would say.
I have given up for the thousandth time.
This policeman not giving up. He doesn't
want to go home.
Some family issues there.
He's like no we will go. He's like come
second come where you got down we go
now.
So we went to the second comedy club.
It's midnight at this point. He got off
his bike and he tells me
He's like you know how this works now.
Me.
>> [laughter]
>> He's like I taught you everything. I
mean this is everything.
He's like yeah you go and rewind the
footage and I'll go to this building. We
will work parallelly now.
>> [laughter]
>> So we split up.
At midnight we split up
to speed up the case.
In this building the second comedy club
no password for the CCTV. So I rewound
the footage.
At this point I want to ask the
audience has anyone here ever lost
laptop or even a phone like in a cab or
something like that yeah?
Isn't it embarrassing? You feel
embarrassed that you can do this as an
adult?
Let me tell you something.
It's nothing compared to the
embarrassment
of seeing CCTV footage of yourself.
Realizing you have lost it.
I pray none of you have to see this in
your life. I watched my footage of me
walking in that building.
>> [laughter]
[laughter]
>> I told you 15 seconds. 2 minutes I was
standing like this.
It was a very poetic moment I remember
where I'm just surveying the ceiling
like I
looking in angles bags are never found.
And then I turned and I looked straight
into the camera.
And 6 hours later future me made I can't
HANDLE MYSELF.
>> [applause]
>> SO EMBARRASSED. I WATCHED IT THREE
TIMES.
AND THEN I asked the staff member who
was with me. I said, "Delete this.
This doesn't go out. I'll throw the CPU
in the pond if you don't delete." Shift
delete.
Stepped on the street diff- de-
completely deflated. The policeman was
there. He's also given up finally. I was
actually relieved.
He's like this building I went they
changed the password.
>> [laughter]
>> I tried admin at 1 2 3 4 also.
It's over.
>> [laughter]
>> He said the magic words. He said, "Go
home." Go home is the magic words right
now.
And he said, "Come tomorrow for
paperwork." Paperwork means usually
it's time.
So this is all happening in Mumbai,
right? My friends from Bangalore were
visiting me during this time and they
were drinking in my house happily. They
didn't know this had happened. I didn't
tell them.
I got home and told them.
They drank more. I've never seen them
happier.
>> [laughter]
>> Because after three drinks you don't
have empathy for your
for something like this. They're like
nobody died, nothing, no injury.
Hilarious.
Because they were there when I bought
it.
You know people roll on the floor
laughing actually.
It's not just emojis. It's based on real
life. One of my friends said, "Hold my
beer." And he rolled.
Came back and said, "Thank you."
>> [laughter]
>> Worst friend One guy said,
"Bro,
what the hell is Asus anyway?
>> [laughter]
>> Who buys Asus?
This is a sign, get a Mac. I'm like,
this is a sign?
This?
All this is a sign?
I lost a new laptop. It's a sign I
should get a newer one, huh?
Hope you never lose your child in a
crowd
with this attitude.
Till 3:00 a.m. they drank my alcohol
shamelessly.
I also drank, but with shame.
It's very different. I left a gap
between me and them. They were like, you
enjoy. I can't enjoy. I'm just looking
at my phone.
It's the only screen I own at this
point.
And I was like, maybe a miracle will
happen, you know? I didn't want to sleep
that night. And uh and at 3:00 a.m. it
happened.
I got a Facebook Messenger notification
at 3:00 a.m. I open it.
It's the auto driver.
He's like, I found your laptop. Tell me
your address. I will return it.
He didn't have to do this, but it's
true. At 4:00 a.m. he came and returned
it to me. It's amazing. Uh
He was awesome.
>> [applause]
>> And I heard this happens. Like in
Mumbai, I've heard many such stories.
In Bangalore,
I don't know. I think in I think in
Bangalore, the auto driver would become
a software engineer.
This is also a beautiful story. It's
just different.
Don't come at me like, hey, no, it's a
lovely story also. Different.
But he returned it at 4:00 a.m. I I gave
him a lot of money, as much as the
laptop, I think.
>> [laughter]
>> And uh he was tall also, so he
needed more than money.
And then before he left, luckily I
remembered to ask him, "How the hell did
you find me at 3:00 a.m.?"
And you know how he found me? This is
true. In my bag, there was an attested
PAN card of mine.
True story.
>> [applause]
>> I'd forgotten to send it to my dad. It
was just there.
He looked at my photo, my name, went to
Facebook, looked me up, looked at the
photo, compared it, and he got in touch.
So, as I leave you now, I want to tell
you,
first of all,
don't delete Facebook.
It pains me to say this, but keep it in
your life. Don't use it. Just let it be
there. That's where they will contact
you.
Also, secondly, ideally change all your
profile photos in every app to your ID
photo.
Make it easier for the good Samaritan in
your [laughter] life. Because he said he
got confused there, because in my PAN
card, I'm like this.
And my Facebook I hadn't looked at for
years. My Facebook profile photo, I was
like
And he was like, "This is not the same
guy." [laughter]
So, it took him a minute to
verify, you know.
So, do that. I mean, you could just add
a tag to your bag
which says, "If found, return to this
address." That would be more practical.
BUT BUT DESPITE APPEARANCES,
>> [cheering and applause]
>> I'M NOT A VERY PRACTICAL PERSON. Thank
you so much. My name is Samay. You've
been wonderful.
>> [cheering]
>> You really guys [applause] been awesome.
Uh this is where people bow usually. I
don't know. I feel awkward to bow, but
uh I haven't done my three for the day,
so
>> [applause]
>> Oh, thank you. That's very kind. Thank
you. You guys been see you guys next
time. Thank you so much. Bye-bye.
>> [cheering]
[music]
[applause]